getkirby.com 2019-04-17

# Privacy Policy | Kirby

## Who we are

The company behind Kirby CMS and the responsible data controller for this website is the Bastian Allgeier GmbH.

_Bastian Allgeier GmbH  
Böhmer Weg 22  
69151 Neckargemünd  
Email: [**support@getkirby.com**](mailto:support@getkirby.com)_

You can contact us any time via email or the postal address above, if you have questions about our privacy policy.

## How we collect data

This is an overview of how we handle your personal data. Please see the sections below for further details.

### On this website

We don't collect any personal data on our website except server logs. We use the following third parties to improve our website performance:

  * KeyCDN:  
_To speed up access to our site across the globe_
  * Algolia:  
_To provide a really good search experience for our site and docs_
  * Cloudinary:  
_To minify our images and increase loading speed for images across the globe_

Read more…

### Shop

<https://getkirby.com/buy>

Our shop is provided by Paddle. They collect the data about your purchases.

Read more…

### Forum

Our support forum is provided by Discourse. Your personal data in the forum is collected on their servers.

Read more…

### Newsletter

<https://getkirby.com/#kosmos>

If you sign up to our newsletter, your data is being collected by our Australian newsletter service Campaign Monitor.

Read more…

## Your rights

GDPR is all about your rights as users and we think this is great! You can exercise your rights by sending us an email at [**support@getkirby.com**](mailto:support@getkirby.com).

### You can access information on all data stored about you

Contact us and we will provide you with all information on data we have about you.

### You have the right to be ‘forgotten’ by us

Let us know and we will delete all your personal data that we store.

### You have the right to correct any personal data stored about you

If there's any personal data about you that should be corrected by us, please let us know.

### You have the right to withdraw your consent

If you signed up to our forum or subscribed to our Kosmos newsletter you can always delete your forum account or unsubscribe from the newsletter at any time. You can do this on your own on the forum or with the unsubscribe button in our newsletters. But we are also happy to do this for you, if you want. Just let us know.

### You have the right to port your data to another service

We will give you a copy of your data in a plain text format so that you can provide it to another service.

### You have the right to file a complaint regarding our use of your data

Please tell us first, so we have a chance to address your concerns. If we fail in this, you can address any complaint to your national data protection authorities.

## Website

### Cookies

Our website **does not** set any cookies.

### Analytics and tracking

We **do not** use any trackers, social media buttons or analytics services on our website.

### TLS encryption

This site uses TLS encryption for security reasons and to protect the transmission of confidential data. You can recognize an encrypted connection in your browser's address line when it changes from "http://" to "https://" and when the lock icon is displayed in your browser's address bar.

If TLS encryption is activated, the data you transfer to us cannot be read by third parties.

### Hosting

The server for our website is provided by

_Linode LLC  
329 East Jimmie Leeds Road  
Galloway, New Jersey 08205_

Linode complies with GDPR. The server is located in their data center in **Frankfurt, Germany**. You can find their privacy policy here: <https://www.linode.com/privacy>

### Server log files

We automatically collect and store information that your browser transmits to us in "server log files" on our Linode server. These are:

  * Browser type and browser version
  * Operating system used
  * Referrer URL
  * Host name of the accessing computer
  * Time of the server request
  * IP address

This data will not be combined with data from other sources.

The basis for data processing is Art. 6 (1) (f) DSGVO, which allows the processing of data to fulfill a contract or for measures preliminary to a contract.

### Third-party services

We use the following third-party services to improve the performance and usability of our site:

#### KeyCDN

We use a content delivery network to provide faster access to our CSS, JavaScript and font files from anywhere around the world. Our CDN is provided by:

_proinity LLC (KeyCDN)  
Ruemikerstrasse 60  
CH-8409 Winterthur  
Switzerland_

KeyCDN complies with GDPR. You can find their privacy policy here: <https://www.keycdn.com/privacy>

#### Cloudinary

We use a third-party service to reduce the file size of the images on our site and also to provide faster access through their content delivery network. This service is provided by

_Cloudinary Ltd.  
111 W Evelyn Ave, Suite 206  
Sunnyvale, CA 94086_

You can find their privacy policy here: <https://cloudinary.com/privacy>

#### Algolia

Our site-wide search is running on a third-party search service. We index only the content that is already publicly available on our site in order to make it searchable for you. The search is provided by:

_Algolia SAS  
55 Rue d’Amsterdam  
75008 Paris  
France_

Algolia complies with GDRP. You can find their privacy policy here: <https://www.algolia.com/security>

## Shop

Our order process is conducted by our online reseller [Paddle.com](https://paddle.com/). Paddle.com is the Merchant of Record for all our orders. Paddle provides all customer service inquiries and handles returns.

_Paddle.com  
340 S Lemon Avenue  
Los Angeles  
California 91789  
USA_

Paddle complies with GDPR. You need to agree to their terms of service and privacy policy whenever you buy a license. We don't store your purchasing data or history anywhere else. You can find Paddle's privacy policy here: <https://paddle.com/privacy/>

## Support Forum

Our support forum is running on an open-source forum software called Discourse and the hosting is provided by the company behind the forum software: <https://www.discourse.org/>

The hosted Discourse forum is GDPR compliant. You can find the privacy policy of Discourse here: <https://meta.discourse.org/privacy>

## Newsletter

You can sign up to our monthly Kirby Kosmos Newsletter to receive updates about Kirby, plugins, themes and other news around Kirby and the web. We never sign you up automatically. You have to use the sign up form on our website and confirm your subscription with the double-opt in process. To sign up we require and verify your email address and you can provide an optional name.

All subscriber data is collected by our Australian newsletter service CampaignMonitor:

_Campaign Monitor Pty Ltd  
404/3-5 Stapleton Ave  
Sutherland NSW 2232  
Sydney  
Australia_

CampaignMonitor is offering extensive analytics tools to check if newsletters have been opened and links have been clicked. We only use those analytics to check how interesting and relevant our newsletters are for the entire list of subscribers over time. We never use them to analyze individual subscribers.

You can unsubscribe from our newsletter at any time. This can be done by using the unsubscribe link in every newsletter or by sending an email to [support@getkirby.com](mailto:support@getkirby.com) and we will handle it for you.

CampaignMonitor complies with GDRP. You can find our more about their privacy policy on their site: <https://campaignmonitor.com/privacy>

## Your Kirby installation

We are not responsible how you handle data privacy on your own Kirby-powered website(s). You are your own data controller and if you are located in the EU or if you have customers in the EU, you must make sure that your site is GDPR-compliant.

The Kirby Panel is designed with data privacy in mind though. The Panel does not communicate with third-party services or our own servers in any form. There are no trackers, no analytics and no cookies except those related to sessions and user management. We have no access to your Panel, to your data, to your server or to your users. We also don't use external services to provide webfonts, JavaScript libraries or any other assets for the Panel. Everything runs on your server and stays under your control.

Make sure to always use HTTPS on your site in order to encrypt login credentials for the Panel and for any other data transmission.

## Questions & Feedback

We try to keep our privacy policy as transparent and easy to understand as possible. Please let us know if we can improve it further or if you have any other questions: [support@getkirby.com](mailto:support@getkirby.com)

## Updates

We will constantly check and update this privacy policy if necessary.  
**Last update: 04.03.2019**
